<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ComponentList>
  <Component>
    <Name>Nursing Assessment</Name>
    <Meaning>NURSING_ASSESSMENT</Meaning>
    <Help>
      Zero or one selection is possible. Intake Note includes documentation of the Presenting Problem, a brief history, allergies,
      medications, and initial vital signs. A Nursing Note contains clinical assessment information and is defined as a
      "timed" entry that addresses one or more Body Areas or Organ Systems. Nursing Notes regarding performance and outcome at
      the time of a separately billable procedure are not counted. There may be one to multiple systems
      assessed/documented in the same timed note and will count as one Nursing Note. CriticalCare Flowsheet/Notes is selected
      when critical care is provided and frequent Nursing Notes are documented.
    </Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>Intake Note</Name>
        <ValueId>0</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>1 to 2 Nursing Notes</Name>
        <ValueId>57502</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>3 to 5 Nursing Notes</Name>
        <ValueId>57503</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>6+ Nursing Notes</Name>
        <ValueId>57504</ValueId>        
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Critical Care Notes</Name>
        <ValueId>57505</ValueId>
      </Item>
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Disposition</Name>
    <Meaning>DISPOSITION</Meaning>
    <Help>
      Zero or one selection is possible. A Routine disposition is included in the base weight and no resource points
      are added. An Immediate Referral is a direct patient transfer to a physician's office or other facility for further
      treatment. Referral/Transfer to ED/OP refers to a non-critical patient transfer to a hospital outpatient service for
      further evaluation, treatment, or procedures. Admit to hospital refers to arranging for a direct admission to a
      hospital. Transfer to facility refers to arranging a transfer or return to a nursing home or similar facility.
    </Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>Routine</Name>
        <ValueId>0</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Immediate Referral</Name>
        <ValueId>57302</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Referral/Trans ED/OPF</Name>
        <ValueId>57303</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Admit to Hospital</Name>
        <ValueId>57304</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Transfer to Facility</Name>
        <ValueId>57305</ValueId>
      </Item>      
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Patient Education</Name>
    <Meaning>PATIENT_EDUCATION</Meaning>
    <Help>
      Only one selection is possible. Points are added for patient education provided by clinic/UC staff during the
      course of or at the end of the encounter. Routine includes documentation of the average education that would
      be provided based on the patient's presenting problem. For more extensive education or education for more
      than one problem, additional resource points are added as noted.
    </Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>Routine &lt; 5 Minutes</Name>
        <ValueId>0</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>5 to 9 Minutes</Name>
        <ValueId>57202</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>10 to 14 Minutes</Name>
        <ValueId>57203</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>15 to 29 Minutes</Name>
        <ValueId>57204</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>&gt; 30 Minutes</Name>
        <ValueId>57205</ValueId>
      </Item>
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Order Management</Name>
    <Meaning>ORDER_MANAGEMENT</Meaning>
    <Help>
      More than one selection is possible; multiple occurrences within a type are counted only once. Order
      management points are added to account for the resources expended to ensure orders are noted,
      communicated, and followed up as needed. This includes nursing or other staff time required prior or
      subsequent to the performance of the order itself. Order management points do not include time spent in actual
      performance of a separately billable test/procedure.
    </Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>Schedule Consult/Referral</Name>
        <ValueId>57601</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Lab Tests</Name>
        <ValueId>57602</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Xray - Plain Films</Name>
        <ValueId>57603</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>EKG/RT/Ancil Svc</Name>
        <ValueId>57604</ValueId>
      </Item>      
      <Item>
        <Name>CT/MRI/Ultra Sound</Name>
        <ValueId>57605</ValueId>
      </Item>
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Process Management</Name>
    <Meaning>PROCESS_MANAGEMENT</Meaning>
    <Help>
      More than one selection is possible. Assist with Exam/Intervention refers to facility personnel assisting the
      provider with an exam or other non separately billed service. Consult Social/Ancillary Services refers to a
      MSW, DC planner, Speech or other support staff who evaluate a patient in the Clinic. Psych/Social crisis refers
      to the situation where the patient requires one on one participation by nursing or other staff due to emotional
      instability from any cause.
    </Help>
    <ItemList>     
      <Item>
        <Name>Assist with Exam/Intervention</Name>
        <ValueId>57401</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Consult Social/Ancil Svc</Name>
        <ValueId>57402</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Psych/Social Crisis</Name>
        <ValueId>57403</ValueId>
      </Item>      
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Critical Care</Name>
    <Meaning>CRITICAL_CARE</Meaning>
    <Help>
      "30 min CriticalCare Management" refers to the provision of the highest acuity care that meets the CPT Critical Care definition and includes a minimum of 30 minutes of nursing or MD Critical Care time
    </Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>30+ minutes</Name>
        <ValueId>57404</ValueId>
      </Item>
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>New or Established Patient</Name>
    <Meaning>NEW_ESTABLISHED</Meaning>
    <Help>
      The Visit Level is determined by adding the Base Weight
      points and any additional resource points. The combined
      points are compared with the Minimum Points Required
      for each Level of Service. Points must meet or exceed
      those required for a given level in order for the Visit Code
      to be charged. Procedures and Supplies are charged
      separately.
    </Help>
    <ItemList>      
      <Item>
        <Name>New</Name>
        <ValueId>New</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Established</Name>
        <ValueId>Est</ValueId>
      </Item>
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Infusion and Injection</Name>
    <Meaning>INFUSION_INJECTION</Meaning>
    <Help>Infusion Injection help</Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>Site</Name>
        <ValueId>IV1</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IV2</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IV3</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IV4</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IM</ValueId>
        <ValueId>SQ</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IA1</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IA2</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Type</Name>
        <Disp>Hydration</Disp>
        <ValueId>HYDRATION</ValueId>
        <Disp>Infusion</Disp>
        <ValueId>INFUSION</ValueId>
        <Disp>IV Push</Disp>
        <ValueId>INJECTION</ValueId>
        <Disp>IM/SQ Injection</Disp>
        <ValueId>IMSQ</ValueId>
        <Disp>Intra-Arterial Injection</Disp>
        <ValueId>INTRAARTERIALINJECTION</ValueId>
      </Item>
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Wizard>
    <MPageName>Clinic Charging and Coding</MPageName>
    <PanelList>
      <Name>Evaluation &amp; Management</Name>
      <Name>Infusion &amp; Injections</Name>
      <Name>Summary</Name>
      <Name>Additional Charges</Name>
    </PanelList>
  </Wizard>
</ComponentList>

