<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ComponentList>
  <Component>
    <Name>Nursing Assessment</Name>
    <Meaning>NURSING_ASSESSMENT</Meaning>
    <Help>
      Zero or one selection is possible. Triage documentation includes the Presenting Problem, a brief history, allergies, medications, initial vital signs,
      and triage category. A documented assessment in Triage counts as the first nursing note. A Nursing Note 
      contains clinical assessment information and is defined as a "timed" entry that Addresses one or more Body Areas or Organ
      Systems.
      Nursing Notes regarding performance and outcome at the time of a separately billable procedure are not counted. There may be
      one to multiple systems assessed/documented in the same timed note and will count as one Nursing Note. Critical Care Notes is selected
      when critical care is provided and frequent Nursing Notes are documented.
    </Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>Triage</Name>
        <ValueId>0</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>1 to 2 Nursing Notes</Name>
        <ValueId>54401</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>3 to 5 Nursing Notes</Name>
        <ValueId>54402</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>6+ Nursing Notes</Name>
        <ValueId>54403</ValueId>        
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Critical Care Notes</Name>
        <ValueId>54404</ValueId>
      </Item>
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Disposition</Name>
    <Meaning>DISPOSITION</Meaning>
    <Help>
      Zero or one selection is possible. A Routine disposition is included in the base weight and no resource points are added. An
      Immediate Referral is a direct patient transfer from the ED to a physician's office or clinic for further treatment.
      Trans/Return to Hosp/SNF refers to a non-critical patient transfer or return to another facility for continued care. Admit-
      Inpt/Obs/Outpt includes admits to inpatient or outpatient units for continued evaluation, treatment, or procedures.
      Admit-ICU/ALS/Air Trans includes critical care/high acuity admits to the intensive/critical care unit, operating room, cath
      lab, or airlift transports.
    </Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>Routine</Name>
        <ValueId>0</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Immediate Referral</Name>
        <ValueId>54501</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Trans/return to Hosp/SNF</Name>
        <ValueId>54502</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Admit-Inpt/Obs/Outpt</Name>
        <ValueId>54503</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Admit-ICU/ALS/Air Trans</Name>
        <ValueId>54504</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Patient Expired</Name>
        <ValueId>54505</ValueId>
      </Item>
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Arrival Mode</Name>
    <Meaning>ARRIVAL_MODE</Meaning>
    <Help>
      Zero or one selection is possible. No points are added for routine modes of arrival (pvt. car, walk-in arrivals are included in
      the base weight). Resource points reflect the varying complexity of the ED admit process when patients arrive with police
      personnel, by ambulance or ALS transport. BLS is basic life support ambulance and ALS is Advanced Life Support (nurse or
      paramedic).
    </Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>Routine</Name>
        <ValueId>0</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>BLS/Police</Name>
        <ValueId>54101</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>ALS</Name>
        <ValueId>54102</ValueId>
      </Item>
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Order Management</Name>
    <Meaning>ORDER_MANAGEMENT</Meaning>
    <Help>
      More than one selection is possible; multiple occurrences within a type are counted only once. Order management points are
      added to account for the ED resources expended to ensure orders are noted, communicated, and followed up as needed.
      This includes nursing or other staff time required prior or subsequent to the performance of the order itself. Order management
      points do not include time spent in actual performance of a separately billable test/procedure. Access Medical Records--
      in paper or an electronic health record (EHR); refers to the additional resources required to obtain/access old records in
      paper or on-line.
    </Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>Lab Tests</Name>
        <ValueId>54201</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Xray - Plain Films</Name>
        <ValueId>54202</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>EKG/RT/Ancil Svc</Name>
        <ValueId>54203</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>CT/MRI/Ultra Sound</Name>
        <ValueId>54204</ValueId>
      </Item>      
      <Item>
        <Name>Access MR-paper/EHR</Name>
        <ValueId>54205</ValueId>
      </Item>
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Process Management</Name>
    <Meaning>PROCESS_MANAGEMENT</Meaning>
    <Help>
      More than one selection is possible. Consult MD refers to the additional work required to assist a consulting MD/resident
      evaluating a pt. in the ED. Consult Social/Ancil Svcs refers to a MSW, DC Planner, Speech or other support staff called
      to evaluate a patient in the ED. Psych/Soc Crisis refers to management of a significant patient behavioral issue that
      requires the frequent or ongoing 1:1 attention of nursing, ancillary, or security staff.
    </Help>
    <ItemList>     
      <Item>
        <Name>Consult MD</Name>
        <ValueId>54301</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Consult Social/Ancil Svc</Name>
        <ValueId>54302</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Psych/Social Crisis</Name>
        <ValueId>54303</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Restraint</Name>
        <ValueId>54304</ValueId>
      </Item>      
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Critical Care</Name>
    <Meaning>CRITICAL_CARE</Meaning>
    <Help>
      "30 min Critical Care Management" refers to the provision of the highest acuity care that meets the CPT Critical Care definition and includes a minimum of 30 minutes of nursing or MD Critical Care time
    </Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>30+ minutes</Name>
        <ValueId>54601</ValueId>
      </Item>      
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Component>
    <Name>Infusion and Injection</Name>
    <Meaning>INFUSION_INJECTION</Meaning>
    <Help>Infusion Injection help</Help>
    <ItemList>
      <Item>
        <Name>Site</Name>
        <ValueId>IV1</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IV2</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IV3</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IV4</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IM</ValueId>
        <ValueId>SQ</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IA1</ValueId>
        <ValueId>IA2</ValueId>
      </Item>
      <Item>
        <Name>Type</Name>
        <Disp>Hydration</Disp>
        <ValueId>HYDRATION</ValueId>
        <Disp>Infusion</Disp>
        <ValueId>INFUSION</ValueId>
        <Disp>IV Push</Disp>
        <ValueId>INJECTION</ValueId>
        <Disp>IM/SQ Injection</Disp>
        <ValueId>IMSQ</ValueId>
        <Disp>Intra-Arterial Injection</Disp>
        <ValueId>INTRAARTERIALINJECTION</ValueId>
      </Item>
    </ItemList>
  </Component>
  <Wizard>
    <MPageName>Facility Charging and Coding</MPageName>
    <PanelList>
      <Name>Evaluation &amp; Management</Name>
      <Name>Infusion &amp; Injections</Name>
      <Name>Summary</Name>
      <Name>Additional Charges</Name>
    </PanelList>
  </Wizard>
</ComponentList>

